So far in this lesson on expressions in common situations we've talked about.
到目前为止，在本课中，我们已经讨论了常见情况下的表达式。
Keep an eye on and out of hand.
密切关注和失控。
Now we're going to look at another situation moving to another place.
现在我们要看看另一种情况转移到另一个地方。
OK so you're moving to another city and you don't need a lot of stuff in your house that you have now.
好的，所以你要搬到另一个城市，你不需要你现在拥有的很多东西。
The one you're living in now so you've decided to give it away your stuff to whoever asks for it first.
你现在住的那个，所以你决定把你的东西送给首先要它的人。
So if you move to a new house where you buy a new house sometimes your old stuff you want to get new
所以如果你搬到一个新房子，在那里你买了新房子，有时你的旧东西你想换新的
stuff so you want to leave it behind.
东西，所以你想把它留在后面。
Maybe the sofa the pots and pans pots and pans are what you used to cook this stuff.
也许沙发锅碗瓢盆是你用来煮这些东西的。
You don't want to take to the new house.
你不想去新房子。
You want to get brand new stuff but it's still useful.
您想获得全新的东西，但它仍然有用。
Maybe somebody wants it.
也许有人想要它。
Maybe you'd like to give it away for free to your friends.
也许你想把它免费送给你的朋友。
Well that's possible.
嗯，这是可能的。
OK so that's the situation.
好的，情况就是这样。
What expression can we use to get it across to announce it to our friends.
我们可以用什么表达方式来传达给我们的朋友。
Let's say I'm going to make a post on social media.
假设我要在社交媒体上发帖。
That's the best way to let a lot of people know something.
这是让很多人知道的最好方法。
Right.
正确的。
Maybe it's Facebook maybe it's Instagram maybe it's whatever you use maybe as we chat maybe it's line.
也许是 Facebook，也许是 Instagram，也许是你使用的任何东西，也许是我们聊天时，也许是线路。
I don't know whatever you use whatever you use you're going to post make a post.
我不知道你用什么你用什么你要发帖。
You could say this to a person.
你可以这样对一个人说。
Sure.
当然。
But it's better if it's said to a whole group of people.
但最好是对一群人说。
All your friends.
你所有的朋友。
All right.
好的。
So my sofa my sofa.
所以我的沙发我的沙发。
You could say my sofa at the old place at the or my old place is now the expression up for grabs if
你可以说我在旧地方的沙发或者我的旧地方现在的表达方式是
anybody needs it.
任何人都需要它。
Or we could say once at my sofa is up for grabs ups I wrote is here my bad.
或者我们可以说有一次在我的沙发上等待我写的东西在这里是我的错。
If if anybody needs it if anybody wants it then what does that mean.
如果有人需要它，如果有人想要它，那是什么意思。
Well it's sort of like I.
嗯，有点像我。
They're all my friends over there and I throw my sofa to them.
他们都是我在那边的朋友，我把沙发扔给他们。
Why throw my sofa out.
为什么把我的沙发扔出去。
I don't want it anybody want it.
我不想要，有人想要。
Whoever reaches up and grabs it and takes it.
无论谁伸手抓住它，然后拿走它。
They're the one who gets my sofa.
他们是得到我沙发的人。
They grab Remember we learned grab before grab means to get to take like that but saying that you want
他们抓住 记住我们在抓住之前学会了抓住意味着像那样抓住，但说你想要
it is kind of the same as reaching out and doing that and grabbing it with your hand.
这有点像伸出手然后用手抓住它。
It's kind of the same.
有点像。
So we use up for grabs when something is available to anyone to take.
因此，当任何人都可以拿走东西时，我们就用尽了。
Could be a sofa could be physically grabbing something.
可能是沙发，可能是物理上抓取的东西。
It could also be for example for a position.
例如，它也可以是一个职位。
So this one is somebody is going to say Oh yeah.
所以这个是有人会说哦，是的。
Me me me me me I want it.
我我我我我我想要它。
I want the sofa.
我要沙发。
Me me me me me.
我我我我我。
Someone might say dibs.
有人可能会说 dibs。
Dibs.
迪布斯。
Dibs on the sofa.
Dibs 在沙发上。
That means I claim that it's an informal expression.
这意味着我声称这是一种非正式的表达方式。
I claim that sofa that's my sofa.
我声称那张沙发就是我的沙发。
The first person.
第一个人。
OK you got it.
好的，你明白了。
Because it's up for grabs but we can use this expression up for grabs for example in maybe a political
因为它是供抢夺的，但我们可以使用这个表达供抢夺，例如在政治
race two people running for the presidency.
赛跑两个人竞选总统。
They want to get it.
他们想得到它。
It's up for grabs.
这是可以抢的。
We don't know who's going to win.
我们不知道谁会赢。
Often we describe situations as up for grabs when we have no idea who's going to win.
当我们不知道谁会赢时，我们经常将情况描述为有待争夺。
So for example there are two teams playing in a championship final right.
例如，有两支球队参加锦标赛 f最终的权利。
Maybe it's the World Cup or whatever and they're equally matched.
也许是世界杯或其他什么，他们是平等的。
We really don't know if this team is going to win or this team if it's not equal and this team is way
我们真的不知道这支球队是否会赢，或者这支球队是否不平等，这支球队就是这样
better than this team then we probably won't say it.
比这支球队更好，那么我们可能不会说出来。
But if it's pretty much equal we'll say I don't know who's going to win this year it's really up for
但如果它几乎相等，我们会说我不知道今年谁会赢，这真的是
grabs.
抓住。
It's really up for grabs.
它真的很抢手。
So that's how it's used.
所以它就是这样使用的。
That's how it's used and DBS is used to claim things in a kind of informal way.
这就是它的使用方式，DBS 用于以一种非正式的方式声明事物。
People will just say dibs Debs or dibs on that.
人们只会说 dibs Debs 或 dibs 。
Dibs on that very common expression up for grabs.
对这个非常常见的表达方式进行讨论。